<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE tmx SYSTEM "tmx14.dtd">
<tmx version="1.4">
  <header creationtool="OmegaT" o-tmf="OmegaT TMX" adminlang="EN-US" datatype="plaintext" creationtoolversion="5.3.0_0_2fd7a9ecc" segtype="sentence" srclang="en"/>
  <body>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Vaccination is safe and side effects from a vaccine are usually minor and temporary, such as a sore arm or mild fever.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>La vacunación es inocua y, aunque pueda producir efectos secundarios, como dolor en el brazo o fiebre baja, suelen ser muy leves y temporales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>More serious side effects are possible, but extremely rare.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Si bien no puede descartarse que ocasionen efectos secundarios graves, estos son sumamente raros.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Any licensed vaccine is rigorously tested across multiple phases of trials before it is approved for use, and regularly reassessed once it is introduced.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Todas las vacunas autorizadas son sometidas a pruebas rigurosas a lo largo de las distintas fases de los ensayos clínicos, y siguen siendo evaluadas con regularidad tras su comercialización.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Scientists are also constantly monitoring information from several sources for any sign that a vaccine may cause health risks.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Además, los científicos hacen un seguimiento constante de la información procedente de diversas fuentes en busca de indicios de que causen efectos adversos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Remember, you are far more likely to be seriously injured by a vaccine-preventable disease than by a vaccine.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Es mucho más probable padecer lesiones graves por una enfermedad prevenible mediante vacunación que por una vacuna.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>For example, tetanus can cause extreme pain, muscle spasms (lockjaw) and blood clots, measles can cause encephalitis (an infection of the brain) and blindness.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Por ejemplo, el tétanos puede ocasionar dolores muy intensos, espasmos musculares (por ejemplo, de músculos que se utilizan para masticar) y coágulos sanguíneos, mientras que sarampión puede inflamar el encéfalo (encefalitis) y causar ceguera.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Many vaccine-preventable diseases can even result in death.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Muchas enfermedades prevenibles mediante vacunación nos pueden matar.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>The benefits of vaccination greatly outweigh the risks, and many more illnesses and deaths would occur without vaccines.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Los beneficios de la vacunación superan con creces los riesgos a los que exponen, y sin vacunas habría muchos más casos de enfermedades y de defunciones.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Are there side effects from vaccines?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Las vacunas, ¿causan efectos secundarios?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Like any medicine, vaccines can cause mild side effects, such as a low-grade fever, or pain or redness at the injection site.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Como todos los medicamentos, las vacunas pueden causar efectos secundarios leves —por ejemplo, fiebre baja, dolor o enrojecimiento en el lugar de inyección—, que desaparecen espontáneamente a los pocos días.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Mild reactions go away within a few days on their own.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Raramente producen efectos secundarios más graves o duraderos:</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Severe or long-lasting side effects are extremely rare.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>la probabilidad de sufrir una reacción grave a una vacuna es de uno entre un millón.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Vaccines are continually monitored for safety, to detect rare adverse events.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Las vacunas se someten a una vigilancia continua para garantizar su inocuidad y detectar posibles efectos adversos, que son infrecuentes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Can a child be given more than one vaccine at a time?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>¿Se puede administrar a los niños más de una vacuna simultáneamente?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Scientific evidence shows that giving several vaccines at the same time has no negative effect.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Se ha demostrado científicamente que administrar varias vacunas al mismo tiempo no causa efectos negativos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Children are exposed to several hundred foreign substances that trigger an immune response every day.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Los niños están expuestos cada día a cientos de sustancias que desencadenan respuestas inmunitarias.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>The simple act of eating food introduces new germs into the body, and numerous bacteria live in the mouth and nose.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Al ingerir un alimento, introduce nuevos gérmenes en su organismo, y su nariz y su boca albergan muchas bacterias.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>When a combined vaccination is possible (e.g. for diphtheria, pertussis and tetanus), this means fewer injections and reduces discomfort for the child.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Cuando se administra a un niño una vacuna múltiple (por ejemplo, contra la difteria, la tosferina y el tétanos) se reduce el número de inyecciones y se le causa menos malestar.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>It also means that your child is getting the right vaccine at the right time, to avoid the risk of contracting a potentially deadly disease.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Además, se garantiza que recibe las vacunas que necesita en el momento adecuado para no exponerlo al riesgo de contraer enfermedades potencialmente mortales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Is there a link between vaccines and autism?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>¿Hay un vínculo entre las vacunas y el autismo?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>There is no evidence of any link between vaccines and autism or autistic disorders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>No existen pruebas que demuestren vínculo alguno entre las vacunas y el autismo u otros trastornos de su espectro.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>This has been demonstrated in many studies, conducted across very large populations.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Ello se ha comprobado en numerosos estudios que han incluido a un número muy alto de individuos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>The 1998 study which raised concerns about a possible link between measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine and autism was later found to be seriously flawed and fraudulent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>En 1998 se publicó un estudio que sembró dudas sobre la posible relación entre una vacuna triple (contra el sarampión, las paperas y la rubeola) y el autismo. Sin embargo, posteriormente se comprobó que el estudio presentaba numerosas deficiencias y era fraudulento.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>The paper was subsequently retracted by the journal that published it, and the doctor that published it lost his medical license.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>La revista que lo había publicado lo eliminó y a su autor se le retiró la licencia para ejercer la medicina.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>Unfortunately, its publication created fear that led to dropping immunization rates in some countries, and subsequent outbreaks of these diseases.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Por desgracia, este artículo asustó a algunas personas y las tasas de inmunización contra algunas enfermedades cayeron en determinados países, con la consiguiente aparición de brotes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv xml:lang="en">
        <seg>We must all ensure we are taking steps to share only credible, scientific information on vaccines, and the diseases they prevent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv xml:lang="es" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20201207T115154Z">
        <seg>Es responsabilidad de todos difundir solamente información científica fiable acerca de las vacunas y de las enfermedades que previenen.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
  </body>
</tmx>
